Guide to the Joseph Desloge river running video collection 1942-1958
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- VHS videocassettes
  - Nevills Expeditions Grand Canyon river trip, circa 1947-1948; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 6.2)
    Aerial views of Vermillion Cliffs, Marble Canyon
    Buffalo
    Little Colorado River
    Aerial view of Grand Canyon
    Map of Grand Canyon
    View from rim
    Emery Kolb
    Unkar Delta
    Tanner Flats area, below Little Colorado River
    Rapids: scouting Sockdologer Rapid
    View of big rapids
    Lining rapids: Otis Marston, Norman Nevills, Garth Marston, Margaret Marston
    Re-loading boats
    Lining sequence speeded up
    Streets scenes in San Francisco with trolleys, turntables
    Office scene, woman typing
    Randall Henderson using typewriter on river, putting note in cairn
    Fossils, fossil hunting
    Monument Valley
    Granaries at Nankoweap, Grand Canyon
    Marston twins with pieces of pottery
    Pottery
    Sign about John Wesley Powell
    F.S. Dellenbaugh inscription, Music Temple, Glen Canyon
    Letter from Nathaniel Galloway, inscription by Galloway
    Various inscriptions: Kolb brothers, Clyde Eddy, Pathe-Bray, Hydes
    Skeleton in Stanton Cave
    Hiking on slickrock in Glen Canyon
    Mining camps, Glen Canyon: Olympia Bar, Zahn's camp
    Nevills finding chest with old clothes in Glen Canyon, modeling old clothes
    Oil camp
    Lizard
    Scorpion
    Garth Marston holding rattlesnake
    Deer swimming in river
    Bighorn sheep
    Marston at oars of boat
    Aerial tram car at Bass Camp, Grand Canyon
    Bridge at Moab, Utah
    Aerial of Navajo Bridge
  - Miscellaneous river trips, circa 1947-1948; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 6.3)
    Two boats running rapids
    Bedrock rapid with boat or barge on top
    Boating at sunset
    Running rapids: Unkar? Nankoweap?
    Lava flows, Vulcan's throne
    Wind blowing sand
    Wind blowing spray in rapid (rain on river)
    Deer Creek Falls, water falling into river (i.e., high water)
    Agathla Peak
    Marston twin daughters in front of Navajo Twins (rock formation near Bluff, Utah)
    Spires in Monument Valley, Mittens
    Angel's Window, North Rim of Grand Canyon
    Views of Grand Canyon from rims
    Havasu Creek
    Diving off rocks
    Boarding boat, launching at Havasu
    Running various rapids
    Floating rapids with inner tubes, life vests, air mattresses
    Running bigger rapid (Dubendorff?)
    Filming rapids from boat
    Rapids from boat and shore
    Otis Marston at oars of boat
    Mrs. Marston in boat in rapid
    Water swirling
    Garth Marson swimming rapid
    Sign: AWarning: do not swim in the Colorado..."
    Lake M Columbine falls?
    Big cruiser
    Tow out
    Hoover Dam. Last title is: "Rapidly yours, Dock (Marston)"
  - Miscellaneous Grand Canyon footage, undated; VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 6.4-7.1)
    Motor boats in Grand Canyon
    Bureau of Reclamation camp on rim of Marble Canyon
    Aerial tramway, rim of Grand Canyon
    Helicopter by river
    Film taken from helicopter
    Helicopter landing
    Rapids: scouting, running, with helicopter overhead
    Film of boat running rapids, taken from helicopter.
    Powerboat in rapid (beginning of 7.1)
    Blank
    Powerboat on Lake Mead
  - Danger River, 1947; Olsen, Edwin E.; VHS videocassette Color, sound (Cassette 7.2)
    "Danger River" consists of outtakes from Olsen's 1946 Academy Award winning short, "Facing Your Danger." Both films were compiled from footage filmed during a 1942 Grand Canyon river trip with Nevills Expeditions.
    Waves in rapids
    View from South Rim, Grand Canyon
    Nevills working on boats, loading boats, boats on trailer approaching Lees Ferry, launching boats, packing boats
    Badger Rapid: scouting, running
    Flip at Tanner Rapid, 1942; Ed Hudson in water holding onto boat
    Numerous scenes of running various rapids
    Wreck of old boat
    Skeleton--not one in South Cave
    Granaries at Nankoweap
    Boats in creek at Havasu
    Fishing at Tapeats Creek
    Deer
    Rapids--Sockdologer (includes slow-motion sequence)
    233 mile rapid (narrator's identification of location may be incorrect)
    Sunset on cliffs
    Last shot of wave in rapid
  - Duplicate of 4.2, VHS videocassette Color, silent (Cassette 7.3)